练习 2-6：辅音到辅音的连读。先听例句：I just didn't get the chance。
Exercise 2-6. Consonant-consonant liaisons. I just didn't get the chance.
再听 I've been late twice；下面分析这两个例子。
I've been late twice. In the preceding examples, you can see that because the
just 结尾的 st 和 didn't 开头的 d 在口腔里非常接近，
ending st of just and the beginning d of didn't are so near each other in the
所以没必要费力重新开始这个声音，它们就会
mouth, it's not worth the effort to start the sound all over again, so they just
不要逐词断开，而要让这些声音连在一起。
flow into each other. You don't say, I just didn't get the chance, but do say, I
同样，第二个例句如果逐词分开说，也会太费劲。
just didn't get the chance. In the same way, it's too much work to say, I've been
所以要几乎像一个词一样说：I've been late twice。
late twice. So you say it almost as if it were a single word, I've been late twice.
TH 音是一种特殊情况。它在各个发音区域之间浮动。
The sound of th is a special case. It's a floater between areas. The sound is
这个声音有时由舌头从牙齿之间弹出形成，有时在
sometimes created by the tongue popping out from between the teeth and other on
上齿背面形成，并和不同字母结合成新的复合
the back of the top teeth, combining with various letters to form a new composite
声音。例如，S 向前移动，F 向后移动，在中间位置相遇。
sound. For instance, S moves forward and the F moves back to meet at the midpoint
注意，图中每一类都包含两个标签：浊音和清音。
between the two. Note, each of the categories in the drawing contains two
这是什么意思？把拇指和食指放在喉咙上，
labels, voiced and unvoiced. What does that mean? Put your thumb and index
说 ZZZ。你应该能通过手指感觉到来自喉咙的振动。
fingers on your throat and say ZZZ. You should feel a vibration from your throat
如果你用气声说同一个音，就会变成 ss，并且会感觉到
in your fingers. If you whisper that same sound, you end up with ss and you feel
手指不再振动。所以 zz 是浊音，ss 是清音。
that your fingers don't vibrate. So, zz is a voiced sound, ss unvoiced. The
consonants in the two left columns are paired like that. B P D T V P G C G G Z Z
Z Z Z Z Z Z Z Z Z er, mmm, mmm, mmm, yeh, wah.